Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- World Service Authority--Commission for International Due Process of law, undated (Box-folder 92: 13)
  Articles about reverence-for-life conservation
- Estes Kefauver, 1954-1965 (Box-folder 92: 14-16)
  Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter
- Article about Luis Kutner, 1975 (Box-folder 93: 1)
- Living will, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 93: 2-6)
- World Habeas Corpus Center (Box 94)
  - Norodom Sihanouk--Cambodia, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 94: 1-2)
  - Leonard V. B. Sutton, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 94: 3)
  - Silvio Tovalaro--Rome, 1967 and undated (Box-folder 94: 4)
    Articles and letters
  - Samuel Barrientos Restrepo--Colombia, 1967 (Box-folder 94: 5)
  - Udo Udoma--Nigeria, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 94: 6)
    Articles and clippings. Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "World Habeas Corpus: The Legal Ultimate for the Unity of Mankind," 1965
  - Miscellaneous materials relating to symposiums in Florida, United States, 1962-1969, and in Germany, 1974-1976 and undated (Box-folder 94: 7-8)
- Organization of American States, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  Annual report and statement of work
- Human rights, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 95: 2)
  Clippings, handbook, letters, minutes of meetings, and printed matter
- Terrorism, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 95: 3-6)
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany relating to communism, human rights, immigration, and U. S. foreign relations, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 95: 7-9)
- Amnesty International, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 96: 1)
  Newsletter, printed matter, and report
- Human rights, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 96: 2)
  Articles, clippings, and printed matter
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the establishment of an international criminal court and related issues of human rights and fair treatment of prisoners, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 96: 3)
- Miscellany, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 96: 4)
- Correspondence (Box 97)
  - Yehudi Menuhin, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - Ved Nanda, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 97: 2)
  - Gurudeep Manocha, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 97: 3)
- Kuwait, 1975 (Box-folder 97: 4)
  Clippings and printed matter, press release, and miscellany
- Lithuania--Human rights, 1980 (Box-folder 97: 5)
  Article and note
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the conduct of trial judges in criminal cases, Israel, the question of Fifth Amendment, and U. S. foreign policy and congressional hearings, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 97: 6-8)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 98: 1)
- Israel, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 98: 2-4)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, the Middle East peace plan, and the status of Soviet Jewry, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 98: 5-6)
- Correspondence (Box 99)
  - Garry Davis, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
  - Mile Wallace, undated (Box-folder 99: 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence--International Lawyers Convention, 1958 (Box-folder 99: 4)
  - Israel Center, 1967 (Box-folder 99: 5)
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 99: 6-10)
- Arabs, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 99: 11)
- Lyle Sullivant Greek indictment, 1972 (Box-folder 99: 12)
- Miscellany, 1972 (Box-folder 99: 13)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 100: 1)
  Includes a letter to President Jimmy Carter
- Clippings and printed matter, primarily about Israel, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 100: 2-5)
- Miscellany, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 100: 6-7)
- Correspondence (Box 101)
  - Garry Davis, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 101: 1)
  - Jim Haynes, 1974 (Box-folder 101: 2)
  - E. Penny Johnson, 1974 (Box-folder 101: 3)
  - Lyman Hinckley, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 101: 4)
  - Miscellany, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 101: 5)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to economic justice, equal justice through law, law enforcement through publicity, Russia and human rights, and women's equality, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 101: 6)
- Miscellany, 1967-1974 and undated (Box-folder 101: 7-9)
- American Bar Association, 1967 (Box-folder 102: 1)
- World Peace through Law Center--World Law Day, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 102: 2)
  Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny," undated
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, international conciliation, and the United Nations, 1946-1978 (Box-folder 102: 3-4)
- Miscellany, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 102: 5-7)
- World Habeas Corpus, 1951-1968 (Box-folder 103: 1-3)
- World Peace through Law Center
  - Committee list, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 103: 4)
  - Committee responses, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 103: 5)
  - Bangkok conference, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 103: 6-7)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 103: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 104: 1)
- Article about Luis Kutners' petition on behalf of internees in Northern Ireland, undated (Box-folder 104: 2)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 104: 3)
  - "The Commission for International Due Process of Law and the International Action Commission,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Forward Step toward a World Legal Order,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Protection of Jews in Arab Countries,", undated
  - "Vistas of the World United: An Outline of World Maturity,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Commission for International Due Process of Law,", undated
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1939 and 1972 (Box-folder 104: 4)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Semitism, colonialism, and racism, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 104: 5)
- Miscellany, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 104: 6-8)
  Includes information about the U.N. Charter revision and Latinos
- Miscellany, 1934-1966 and undated (Box-folder 105: 1-7)
  Includes information about anti-trust laws, court decisions, grounds for disqualification of judges, probate, process of indictment and appeal, and related matters
- Clippings and printed matter relating the to the separation of church and state and the legal system, 1955-1978 (Box-folder 106: 1-4)
- Miscellany, 1974 (Box-folder 106: 5)
- Miscellany, 1966 (Box-folder 107: 1)
  Legal papers
- Harold S. Schwarty, 1969 (Box-folder 107: 2)
- Henry A. Kissinger, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 107: 3-4)
- Philippines, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 107: 5-6)
- Clippings relating to the Jewish community and Israel, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 107: 7)
- Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 107: 8-9)
  Press releases
- Draja Mihailovich, 1946-1978 (Box-folder 108: 1)
  Clipping and deposition
- Israel, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 108: 2-3)
  Clippings, notes, printed matter, and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 108: 4)
- Correspondence (Box 109)
  - J. Christopher Napier, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 109: 1)
  - Robert A. Lowry, 1971 (Box-folder 109: 2)
  - Gerhard O. W. Mueller, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 109: 3)
  - Hurst Hannum and Frank C. Newman, 1972 (Box-folder 109: 4)
  - Paschal J. O'Hare, 1972 (Box-folder 109: 5)
  - A. H. Robertson, 1971 (Box-folder 109: 6)
  - Pat Roche, 1972 (Box-folder 109: 7)
  - Adlai Stevenson III, 1971 (Box-folder 109: 8-9)
  - Anthony Smythe, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 109: 10)
  - Leslie Warren, 1972 (Box-folder 109: 11)
  - Robert Henry West, 1972 (Box-folder 109: 12)
  - Hans Wiebringhaus, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 109: 13)
  - Miscellany, 1971 (Box-folder 109: 14)
- Northern Ireland
  - James B. McCartney, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 109: 15-16)
    Clippings, correspondence, newsletter, report, printed matter, and miscellany
  - Miscellany, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 109: 17-20)
- Correspondence (Box 110)
  - Karl H. Beck, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 110: 1)
  - Patrick J. O'Malley, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 110: 2)
- Kashmir (India), 1957-1977 (Box-folder 110: 3)
  Clippings, letters, memoranda, newsletters, notes, printed matter, and report
- Kuwait, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 110: 4)
  Clippings, letters, printed matter, proposal, and study
- Lithuania, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 110: 5)
  Clippings, notes, press release, and printed matter
- Nigeria, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 110: 6)
- Formosa, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 111: 1-2)
  Articles, clippings, printed matter, and summons relating to a lawsuit
- Correspondence
  - Judith Coplon, 1949-1964 (Box-folder 111: 3)
  - Philip M. Klutznick, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 111: 4)
  - F. Ashe Lincoln, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 111: 5)
  - Sidney Liskofsky, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 111: 6)
  - Henry Cabot Lodge, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 111: 7)
  - Look Magazine, 1965 (Box-folder 111: 8)
  - Tran Tam, 1976 (Box-folder 111: 9)
  - Clare B. Luce, 1972 (Box-folder 111: 10)
  - Eliot H. Lumbard, 1960 (Box-folder 111: 11)
  - John L. McClellan, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 111: 12)
  - Myers S. McDougal, 1951-1974 (Box-folder 111: 13)
  - Eugene J. McCarthy, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 111: 14)
  - Henry R. Luce, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 111: 15)
  - Miscellany--World habeas corpus, 1976 (Box-folder 111: 16)
- Cuba, undated (Box-folder 111: 17)
  Report on five years of Castro's Cuba
- Correspondence (Box 112)
  - Stephen P. Marks, 1973 (Box-folder 112: 1)
  - Myers S. McDougal, 1955-1967 (Box-folder 112: 2)
  - Gerald J. McMahon, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 112: 3)
  - Richard I. Miller, 1971 (Box-folder 112: 4)
  - Leslie Knox Munro, 1963 (Box-folder 112: 5)
  - Edward R. Murrow, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 112: 6)
  - Wayne Morse, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 112: 7)
  - Saleh Wahbi Mohamed, 1974 (Box-folder 112: 8)
  - Abner Mikva, 1970 (Box-folder 112: 9)
  - David Martin, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 112: 10)
  - Golda Meir, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 112: 11)
  - Soia Mentschikoff, 1979 (Box-folder 112: 12)
  - Yehudi Menuhin, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 112: 13)
  - Abraham Lincoln Marovitz, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 112: 14)
  - Jim Mattox, 1979 (Box-folder 112: 15)
  - "M" miscellany, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 112: 16)
  - Ved P. Nanda, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 112: 17)
  - Richard Nixon, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 112: 18)
  - Hugh O'Brian, 1968 (Box-folder 112: 19)
  - Thomas Oduro-Kwarten, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 112: 20)
  - M. Cherif Bassiouni, 1968 (Box-folder 112: 21)
  - Hadassah Marcus and Charles Palm, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 22)
- Article about Luis Kutner, 1982 (Box-folder 112: 23)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 112: 24)
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", 1980
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", 1981
  - "Magna Carta: The Ignored Legacy of Anti-Semitism,", 1982
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany relating to the right of habeas corpus, the situation in Mexico, peace in the Middle East, and world peace, 1963/1976 (Box-folder 112: 25-30)
- Scrapbooks (Box 113)
  - Human Rights, 1960-1962
  - William Oatis (2 scrapbooks), 1951-1954 (Box 114)
    Includes 4 photographic prints depicting a group of protestors demanding freedom for Oatis, 1952 September 15
  - Moise Tshombe and miscellany, 1957-1980
  - Adolf Eichman, 1960-1961 (Box 115)
    Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "Tax Equity for Non-Resident Aliens: A Proposal," undated
  - Indira Gandhi--India, 1975-1976
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 116: 1)
  - "World Court of Human Rights: Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "Due Process of Economy: A Proposal for a United States Economy Court,", 1961
  - "The Desecration of the Ferguson Monument Trust: The Need for Watchdog Legislation,", 1963
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "Charitable Trust Legislation in the Several States" (with Henry H. Koven), 1966 (Box-folder 116: 2)
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967
  - "Due Process of Abortion,", 1968
  - "Habeas Marinus: Due Process of Inner Space--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Habeas Scholastica: An Ombudsman for Academic Due Process--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "A World Outer Space Prison: A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Due Process of Euthanasia: The Living Will--A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Habeas Marinus: A Proposal In Ocean Law,", 1969
  - "International Eminent Domain,", 1970 (Box-folder 116: 3)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "Due Process of Human Transplants: A Proposal,", 1970
  - "Due Process of Debate: A Senator's Dilemma,", 1974
  - "Nixon v. Cox: Due Process of Executive Authority,", 1974
  - "A Legal Note on the Nixon Pardon: Equal Justice Vis-a-Vis Due Process,", 1975
  - "The Genocide of Whales: A Crime against Humanity,", 1978
  - "Euthanasia: Due Process for Death with Dignity--The Living Will,", 1978-1979
- Clippings and printed matter relating to crime control, due process of law, estate planning, retirement benefits, and world peace, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 116: 4-7)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 117: 1)
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", undated
  - "The Desecration of the Ferguson Monument Trust: The Need for Watchdog Legislation,", 1963
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Legal Ultimate for the Unity of Mankind,", 1965
  - "Crime-Torts: Due Process of Compensation for Crime Victims,", 1966
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1966
  - "Overdue Due Process for Women Lawyers,", 1968
  - "Homo Arbiter: Emerging Judicial Man--Suggestions for Qualifications and Credentials,", 1970
  - "Contempt Power: The Black Robe--A Proposal for Due Process,", 1971 (Box-folder 117: 2)
  - "Commentary: A Trilogy on Great Philosophers and the Law,", 1972
  - "Due Process of Rebellion,", 1972
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "Executive Privilege: Growth of Power over a Declining Congress,", 1973-1974
  - Due Process of Rebellion, 1974
  - "Advance and Dissent: Due Process of the Senate,", 1974
  - "Due Process in the Contested New Hampshire Senate Election: Fact, Fiction, or Farce,", 1975 (Box-folder 117: 3)
  - "The Living Will: Coping with the Historic Event of Death,", 1975
  - "The Control and Prevention of Transmittal Pollution: A Case for World Habeas Ecologicus,", 1977
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw and Global Justice,", 1978
  - "The Human Rights of Karl Marx,", 1979
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", 1980
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1981
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", 1981
- Printed matter about extradition, Kutner College, social change, and world peace, 1956-1980 (Box-folder 117: 4)
- Miscellany, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 117: 5)
- American veterans, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 118: 1-7)
  Materials relating to anti-American feelings, the arms race, chemical warfare, and world peace. Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "The Decline and Fall of the United States" (undated)
- Senior citizens, 1980-1981 and undated (Box-folder 119: 1-11)
  Brochure, correspondence, clippings, newsletter, and printed matter relating to the publication and funding of a national newspaper, The Elder American, and senior achievement awards
- Applications and petition, 1969 and undated (Box-folder 119: 12-14)
- Miscellany, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 119: 15-19)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to inflation, the Jewish problem, labor unions, terrorism, U.S. foreign policy with regard to the Soviet Union, and related materials, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 120: 1-3)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 120: 4)
- Ronald Pritikin--Center for Global Security, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 121: 1-6)
  Correspondence, medical testimony, printed matter, and miscellany
- Writing by Luis Kutner--Article on the World Genocide Tribunal, 1982 (Box-folder 121: 7)
- Clippings, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 122: 1-3)
  American Jewish Ledger, 1975-1981
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - The Human Right to Individual Freedom: A Symposium on World Habeas Corpus, edited by Luis Kutner, undated (Box-folder 122: 4)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition," paper, International Bar Association conference, Mexico City, 1964 (Box-folder 122: 5)
    Includes papers and reports by others and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1964 and undated (Box-folder 122: 6)
- Correspondence (Box 123)
  - Clerk, U.S. District Court, Atlanta, Georgia, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 1)
  - Jane M. Byrne, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 2)
  - Publishers re: "World Habeas Corpus: Implementing Individual Freedom,", 1981 (Box-folder 123: 3)
  - Anne Middleswarth, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 4)
  - Madeleine Tolmach, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 5)
  - Harvey A. Hyman, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 6)
  - David Hughes, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 7)
- Lupton estate, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 123: 8-10)
  Correspondence, court judgment, notes in a divorce case, and miscellany
- Pacific Connections, Inc., 1979-1981 (Box-folder 123: 11)
  Financial records
- Hardin B. Jones, 1955-1981 (Box-folder 123: 12-14)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and miscellany
- Egypt, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 123: 15)
- Miscellany, 1947-1981 (Box-folder 123: 16-17)
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 124: 1)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 124: 2)
  - World Habeas Corpus, 1962
  - I, the Lawyer, 1966
  - How to Be a Wise Widow, 1970
- Correspondence
  - World Court, 1976-1998 (Box-folder 124: 3-5)
  - Miscellany, 1962-1982 (Box-folder 124: 6)
- Miscellany, 1962-1981 (Box-folder 124: 7)
  Includes 4 photographic prints depicting Philip Tamoah-Boatemg, undated
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Proposal for an International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
  - "The Case for an International Writ of Habeas Corpus: A Reply,", 1960
  - "An International Writ of Habeas Corpus: Protection of Personal Liberty in a World of Diverse Systems of Public Order,", 1961
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: An International Remedy for Wrongful Seizures of Property,", 1961 (Box-folder 125: 2)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Absolute for Survival,", 1962
  - "Due Process of Outer-Space Law: The International Cosmos Court: A Proposal,", 1962
  - "Unfair Comment: A Warning to News Media,", 1962
  - "Due Process of Economy: Antitrust Control of Labor,", 1962 (Box-folder 125: 3)
  - "The Illusion of Due Process in Commitment Proceedings,", 1962
  - "Charitable Trust Legislation In the Several States" (with Henry H. Koven), 1966
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "The Neglected Ninth Amendment: The 'Other Rights' Retained by the People,", 1967
  - "Due Process of Human Transplants: A Proposal,", 1970
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 125: 4)
- William Kirby, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 125: 5-6)
  Clippings, correspondence, and printed matter
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, issues affecting veterans, and justice for Uganda, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 125: 7)
- Correspondence (Box 126)
  - Abdul Hafiz Pirzada, 1973 (Box-folder 126: 1)
  - World Policy Committee, 1972 (Box-folder 126: 2)
- Korean Trade News, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 126: 3-4)
  Correspondence, financial records, and issues of weekly newsletter
- Cyprus, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 126: 5-6)
- Human rights, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 126: 7)
- Miscellany, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 126: 8-9)
- Ireland (Box 127)
  - Correspondence
    - Charles J. Haughey, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 127: 1)
    - United Irish and American Society, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 127: 2)
    - Benjamin Briscoe, 1978 (Box-folder 127: 3)
    - Miscellany, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 127: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter on terrorism and the Irish Freedom Center, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 127: 5-9)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 127: 10)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 128: 1)
  - "If you are Imprisoned in a Foreign Land?", undated
  - "The Proposed United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus Is a Realistic Weapon for Enforceable Human Rights,", 1954?
  - "One-World--The Universe and Albert Einstein,", 1979
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 128: 2)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949-1963 (Box-folder 128: 3)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, world peace, and the United Nations, 1949-1975 and undated (Box-folder 128: 4-6)
- Miscellany, 1976 and undated (Box-folder 128: 7)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 129: 1)
  - "The Prisoner's Wife: The Story of Lucile Vogeler,", undated
    Chapter titles
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Forward Step toward a World Legal Order,", undated
  - Unidentified draft chapters, 1951 and undated
  - "World Peace through Law," paper, Washington World Conference, 1965
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 129: 2)
- Correspondence, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 129: 3)
- Tilly Losch, 1947-1960 (Box-folder 129: 4)
  Clippings, correspondence, and telegram
- International Bar Association, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 129: 5)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, and printed matter
- Kutner miscellany, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 129: 6)
  Announcement and printed matter
- Citation and petition, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 129: 7-8)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to coordination of human rights, international organizations, the situation in Ireland, U.S. policy toward refugees, and world habeas corpus, 1965-1982 (Box-folder 129: 9-12)
- Miscellany, 1981 and undated (Box-folder 129: 13)
- Cyprus (Box 130)
  - Correspondence
    - Christopher H. Costis, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 130: 1)
    - Spyros Kyprianou, Christopher H. Costis, and Ernest J. Vardalas, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 130: 2)
    - Zenon Rossides, 1979 (Box-folder 130: 3)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 130: 4)
- World Court of Public Opinion, 1961-1979 and undated (Box-folder 130: 5-12)
- Dorothy Ann O'Shea Trust--Miscellaneous materials, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 131: 1-8)
  Includes 2 photographic prints depicting Aldean M. Anastas
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the declaration of no war, the nuclear threat, and world peace, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 131: 9-11)
- Miscellany, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 131: 12-13)
- Luis Kutner vs. estate of Philip H. Meade, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 132: 1-8)
- Senior Citizens Crime Commission (SCCC), 1979-1982 (Box-folder 133: 9-12)
  Annual report, clippings, correspondence, press release, and miscellany
- WBBM TV, 1981 (Box-folder 132: 13)
  Clippings, correspondence, press release, and miscellany
- Luis Kutner vs. Thomas Fitzpatrick-- Sun Times, 1974-1991 and undated (Box-folder 133: 1-3)
- Schatz vs. Schatz, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 133: 4-8)
  Clippings, correspondence, financial and legal records, memoranda, notes, printed matter, telegram, and miscellany
- Peter Hall, 1979 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  Article, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, telegram, and miscellany
- Ted Jefferson, 1979 (Box-folder 134: 2)
  Clippings, financial records, letters, printed matter, telegram, and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 134: 3)
- Research materials--Dan Nimrod, relating to Arab-Israeli relations
  - 1979-1982 (Box-folder 134: 4-6)
  - 1982 (Box-folder 135: 1-8)
- Writings by Luis Kutner on the world genocide tribunal and related materials, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 136: 1-2)
- Clippings and printed matter
  - Revolt of the Planet Earth, 1980 and undated (Box-folder 136: 3)
  - Habeas Foeta, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 136: 4-7)
    Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "Habeas Foeta: Protecting the Foetus and the Right to Live," undated
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 137)
  - Due Process of Rebellion, 1974 (Box-folder 137: 1)
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967 (Box-folder 137: 2)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973